Collection of photographs of Lebanon center
Lebanon Historical Society
Collection of photographs of Lebanon center
1867-1875
unknown
2004.003.003
1 ft 1 box
Lebanon Historical Society
This collection includes 20 photographic prints of the center of Lebanon, CT, between 1867 and 1875. Views show historically significant buildings and landscapes but do not include people or activities.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
The photographs were transferred from the Jonathan Trumbull Library to the Lebanon Historical Society in 2004. The photographs had been donated to the Jonathan Trumbull Library by Mrs. Arthur Smith and Mr. Clarence Geer at an unknown date.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection includes 20 albumen prints of the center of Lebanon, CT, between 1867 and 1875. Documented are the Green, First Congregational Church meeting house, grist mill, town hall and several private homes.
- Inventory
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Congregational church before 1875 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking east down Rt. 207 from belfry (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking north East Town Street (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking north West Town Street (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking south to the town hall on the little Green (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking southwest over Redwood Barn towards Goshen (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Corner of Rt. 87 & 207, former William Williams home (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking west over Rt. 207 towards Exeter (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Grist mill and mill pond at the foot of the hill west of the center on Rt. 207 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; South section of the Green (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; View of the Governor Jonathan Trumbull House from the belfry (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Boarding House at the intersection of Rt. 87 and Rt. 207 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking north towards the meeting house from south of Goshen Hill Rd. and Rt. 87 junction (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photograph, 1865-1869; Congregational Church parsonage and Solomon Williams House (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photograph, 1867-1868; Alden Tavern (Wattles House) before its 1868 demolition (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photograph, 1867-1868; Alden Tavern (Wattles House) before its 1868 demolition (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Redwood (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Trumbull Cemetery looking northeast (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Trumbull tomb (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photograph, 1865-1875; Looking across mill pond o Center Cemetery with War Office beyond (Box 1, Folder 20)